At 7:45 a.m., I open the doors to a building
في الـ 7:45 صباحا, أقوم بفتح أبواب لمبنى
dedicated to building, yet only breaks me down.
أن تهب نفسك لبناء لا يجعلني إلا منهارا
I march down hallways cleaned up after me every day
أتمشى في الممرات التي تصبح نظيفة بعد مروري
by regular janitors,
بواسطة البوابين التقليديين
but I never have the decency to honor their names.
ولكن لم أحظى بشيمة ذكر أسمائهم من قبل
Lockers left open like teenage boys' mouths
الأقفال تركت مفتوحة كأفواه المراهقين
when teenage girls wear clothes that covers
عندما ترتدي المراهاقات لملابسهن التي تغطي
their insecurities but exposes everything else.
مفاتنهن ولكن تظهر كل شيء آخر.
Masculinity mimicked by men who grew up with no fathers,
الذكورة المقلدة من هؤلاء من نضجوا بدون آباء,
camouflage worn by bullies who are dangerously armed
المظهر الزائف الذي يرتديه المتمردين والمسلحون بشكل خطير
but need hugs.
ولكنهم في حاجة لحضن.
Teachers paid less than what it costs them to be here.
لم يمنح المدرسون مقدار تكلفة وجودهم هنا.
Oceans of adolescents come here to receive lessons
محيطات من المراهقين يأتون لتلقي الدروس
but never learn to swim,
ولكن لم يتعلموا أبدا كيفية العوم,
part like the Red Sea when the bell rings.
جزء كالبحر الأحمر عندما يدق الجرس.
This is a training ground.
هذه ساحة للتدريب.
My high school is Chicago,
مدرستي الثانية هي ولاية شيكاغو,
diverse and segregated on purpose.
متنوعة وتفصل بين الجنسين عن عمد.
Social lines are barbed wire.
الفواصل الإجتماعية كالأسلاك الشائكة.
Labels like "Regulars" and "Honors" resonate.
مصطلحات كـ "العادي" و "الأوسمة" لها رنين.
I am an Honors but go home with Regular students
لدي الأوسمة ولكن أعود إلى البيت مع طلبة عاديين
who are soldiers in territory that owns them.
الذين هم جنود في مقاطعة تمتلكهم.
This is a training ground to sort out the Regulars
هذه ساحة تدريب للفصل بين العاديين
from the Honors, a reoccurring cycle
و بين الموسمين, دائرة تتكرر
built to recycle the trash of this system.
أنشئت لتدوير مخلفات هذا النظام.
Trained at a young age to capitalize,
تدربت في صن صغيرة على ممارسة الرأسمالية,
letters taught now that capitalism raises you
الرسائل علمتنا الآن أن الرأسمالية تعلي من قدرك
but you have to step on someone else to get there.
ولكنك في حاجة لدوس شخص آخر لتصل
This is a training ground where one group
هذه ساحة تدريب حيث تكون هناك مجموعة
is taught to lead and the other is made to follow.
تتعلم أن تقوم بينما تتعلم الأخري أن تكون تابعة
No wonder so many of my people spit bars,
لا عجب في أن الكثير من قومي
because the truth is hard to swallow.
ولأن الحقيقة من الصعب إبتلاعها.
The need for degrees has left so many people frozen.
الحاجة لدرجة علمية خلفت العديد في حالة ثبات.
Homework is stressful,
الواجب المنزلي يتسم بالضغط,
but when you go home every day and your home is work,
ولكن عندما تعوب للبيت كل يوم ويكون واجبك هو المنزل,
you don't want to pick up any assignments.
حينها لا تريد القيام بأية مهمة.
Reading textbooks is stressful,
قراءة النصوص يتسم بالضغط,
but reading does not matter when you feel
ولكن القراءة لا تهم عندما تشعر
your story is already written,
أن قصتك قد كتبت بالفعل,
either dead or getting booked.
سواء كنت حيا أو على قيد الحياة.
Taking tests is stressful,
المرور بالإختبارات يتسم بالضغط,
but bubbling in a Scantron does not stop
ولكن حالة الإحتدام في سكانترون لا تتوقف
bullets from bursting.
دوي الرصاصات.
I hear education systems are failing,
أسمع النظام التعليمي يتداعى,
but I believe they're succeeding at what they're built to do --
ولكن أعتقد أنهم ناجحون فيما شيدوه ويقومون به --
to train you, to keep you on track,
ليدربوك, ليبقوك على المسار,
to track down an American dream that has failed
لتتبع الحلم الأمريكي الذي قد خذل
so many of us all.
العديد منا جميعا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)